<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://my-site.com/writing/blog</id>
    <title>Adam Liechty Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://my-site.com/writing/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Adam Liechty Blog</subtitle>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Earthy Round]]></title>
        <id>https://my-site.com/writing/blog/earthy-round</id>
        <link href="https://my-site.com/writing/blog/earthy-round"/>
        <updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before songs of joy or hopes or fears]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before songs of joy or hopes or fears<br>
Were sent to meet the grains of air,<br>
And tales of courage pricked the ears<br>
Of budding heroes under worried care,<br></p><p>I held my gifts for those unknown<br>
To angels searching yawning space<br>
Who pondered what might still be sown<br>
In such a wild and violent place.<br></p><p>My habitat ends not perceived<br>
For creatures of another kind,<br>
I veiled my purpose interleaved<br>
In creativity divine.<br></p><br><br><p>And when the time for those had come<br>
Whose mirrored countenance gave light<br>
To creatures, never wearisome<br>
Of purest love and strongest might,<br></p><p>I welcomed them with all I stored<br>
Through ages known to none of late.<br>
I gave all that I could afford<br>
To them who worried naught of fate,<br></p><p>Until they grasped for other good<br>
Than freely given from the dust.<br>
They never could have understood<br>
That wisdom’s knowledge hides in trust.<br></p><br><br><p>My destiny was shaper of<br>
That seedling grove of royalty<br>
Till they, beloved, maturely love<br>
And humbly join in shaping me.<br></p><p>But they trampled on my glory!<br>
I’m cursed despite obedience!<br>
My lot is now to groan and be<br>
Receiv’r of blood of innocents.<br></p><p>But pity not, you hearers, lest<br>
You feign discerning sisterhood<br>
With me. Your span lags mine at best<br>
By seven orders’ magnitude.<br></p><br><br><p>My birth was shrouded–ere I was<br>
Forged in the fires of Theia’s blow–<br>
From all my guests alive because<br>
That tumult seeded Luna’s glow.<br></p><p>She danced around my molten lathe<br>
Until my surface cooled enough<br>
For her to daily doubly bathe<br>
My rocky coasts, which start out rough.<br></p><p>I’ve overseen the rise and fall<br>
Of aeon-spanning dynasties.<br>
Let words be few, if spoke at all<br>
And listen: You are just a breeze.<br></p><br><br><p>Yet still I give my fruits on limb<br>
Though fraught with toil and labored pain<br>
I’m patient, yet I long for him<br>
To make me fully new again,<br></p><p>When heaven’s song will me restore,<br>
Inoculated with the sound<br>
Of wavelengths latent in my core<br>
And yours, when what is lost is found,<br></p><p>And dissonance resolves in your<br>
Redemption and in mine, and each<br>
Of us rejoice: Exalted poor<br>
Have reconciled grasp and reach!<br></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Liechty</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/adamliechty</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="writing" term="writing"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Gardener]]></title>
        <id>https://my-site.com/writing/blog/gardener</id>
        <link href="https://my-site.com/writing/blog/gardener"/>
        <updated>2020-01-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once there was a gardener who spent her days walking through a great meadow, tending and watering her flowers. She pushed a heavy wheelbarrow along full of watering cans, stopping to care for each of her plants in that space. Some had arrived in the meadow as seeds borne on the wind, and some she planted herself, but she loved them all. As she stopped at each one, she would gently pour the water over its petals and sing to it the love, beauty, and truth of the heavens, and each would drink up all of these, receiving her gifts and thriving as a result. The flowers absorbed the water and breathed the common air that wafted gently and graciously through the field, and they built their bodies with all of these and the sweet songs that made them even more beautiful. The gardener loved each of her plants, and could not remember any time before she had loved them or the day when she had started caring for them.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once there was a gardener who spent her days walking through a great meadow, tending and watering her flowers. She pushed a heavy wheelbarrow along full of watering cans, stopping to care for each of her plants in that space. Some had arrived in the meadow as seeds borne on the wind, and some she planted herself, but she loved them all. As she stopped at each one, she would gently pour the water over its petals and sing to it the love, beauty, and truth of the heavens, and each would drink up all of these, receiving her gifts and thriving as a result. The flowers absorbed the water and breathed the common air that wafted gently and graciously through the field, and they built their bodies with all of these and the sweet songs that made them even more beautiful. The gardener loved each of her plants, and could not remember any time before she had loved them or the day when she had started caring for them.</p><p>Now the meadow was vast, and as the years went by, the gardener called more and more plants her own, bringing them under her care. One day, she came upon a new plant, but it had not yet bloomed. She gently poured water on it and sang to it the love, beauty, and truth of the heavens. But the water seemed to run off the sides of its body and onto the ground. The next day, she returned and repeated her ritual, but still the water did not penetrate its body, and she observed that it had a thick outer skin. She returned each day for some weeks, hoping that her love and life-giving water would be received and that this plant would grow and blossom.</p><p>But weeks turned into months, and the gardener grew more discouraged. In desperation one day, she peeled back some of the rough skin from the plant and poured water into its side, but it still did not seem to take. She sang to it, but with not quite the same belief as before. She was too distraught to return to it for several days, but when she did, she brought even more water, but still it ran down onto the ground. In despair that her efforts were having no effect, she pushed the plant, but it did not bend. She hit it, but it did not break. Finally, she dug into it with her knife. It was hard, but it yielded its tough skin and some of the flesh inside, and a tiny amount of sticky water oozed out. The gardener tried to sing as she poured water into the wound, and while the words were the same as before, the melody was hardly discernible. As she left full of frustration, she unwittingly trod on some of the flowers to which she had once sung with the love, beauty, and truth of the heavens.</p><p>The weather grew colder, and the gardener’s heart grew fainter as she pushed her wheelbarrow through the meadow with greater exhaustion each day. She felt terrible each time she accidentally stepped on or rolled over some of her flowers. In time she found it almost impossible to speak to them, and in her weariness she became unable to make it to some of them often enough to sustain them. And whether by that or by the growing cold, many plants began to die.</p><p>One day out in the meadow, a fierce storm blew in unexpectedly, and the gardener was far from shelter. Hail began to fall, and through limited visibility she barely saw a large tree nearby and ran to it, clinging to its trunk. Icy chunks hit the tree, which shielded her. She ran back for the wheelbarrow and propped it against the trunk and crouched in between the two. Wrapping her coat over her body, huddled at the base of the tree, she fell asleep in exhaustion and slept there for the night as the wind howled around her.</p><p>In the morning, the gardener awoke to a clear sky and branches and leaves littered on the ground around her and her tree. She was disheartened to look out and see many of the plants for which she had cared dashed to pieces by the storm, and she could not help but feel that she had failed them. Finally, turning around toward the tree, she thanked it for keeping her safe. She looked up into the tree and saw a haggard, damp raccoon huddled in a cleft. In a hole high in one of the main branches she saw a tiny bird peering out at her. And in the crevices and folds of the bark, innumerable ants, beetles, spiders, and locusts had found their refuge. While studying this tough outer covering of her tree, she saw a place where the bark had been stripped away, which had begun to decay, but was beginning to heal from the outside in. She walked around the trunk and soon saw the straight lacerations of a blade that had cut through the bark and into the sapwood, but this wound was still raw, though darkened by the elements. The gardener sobbed and clung to the tree.</p><p>The next day, the gardener returned to her tree, without water, wheelbarrow, or song. She simply sat underneath its branches quietly. She looked down at the ground and saw the roots crisscrossing above and below the surface of the soil, full of dirt, rocks, and decayed leaves, and imagined the roots extending deep into the earth, holding on with all their might, wrapping around boulders, stones, and themselves, and never letting go, and drinking deep the water of heaven and pulling it upward to its branches and leaves. She longed also to be held that tightly by her tree, and looking up into its limbs, she felt an excitement from her childhood return to her. She climbed the trunk and soon her hands and feet were moving with joy as she reached the highest branch that would support her. Settling into a nook, she let the tree hug her, and she sat for hours, looking out at the meadow and sky and feeling the gentle rock and sway of the tree as it moved in its own way in the breeze, as if dancing to the love, beauty, and truth of the heavens. Day after day, she returned to her tree, climbed its branches, and each day, she heard and relearned the songs of the love, beauty, and truth of the heavens... even new, deeper songs that made the old ones all the more beautiful.</p><p>As winter set in, the gardener longed to stay with her tree, so she brought a ladder and built a small house up in a sturdy branch, overhanging the meadow below. Its wooden shingles, plank floor, and the blankets she carried up gave her the warmth and the shelter to feel the sway and hear the breeze in the leaves and watch the bucks and the does wander and jump and run through the meadow. And when the snow fell gently, it insulated her small treehouse all the more, and a peace beyond her understanding returned to her that she had thought was gone.</p><p>In time, the snow melted, and the grasses began to green again. The weather warmed and sprouts emerged from the ground all throughout the meadow. The love, beauty, truth, peace, and joy of the heavens was everywhere and could not be silenced. The tree breathed and waved, and the gardener opened her mouth and the meadow heard the strong and clear songs of heaven, both old and new.</p><p>The next day the gardener brought her wheelbarrow and watering cans and took to her work once again. Some days the gentle rain was enough, and she brought only her songs, which the flowers also absorbed and thereby gained an extra splendor. She also sang to her tree—which was by now again extending its leaves—the love, beauty, and truth of the heavens. And she perceived that it, too, took in her songs as a familiar and ancient melody, made new again and closer than ever. After several more weeks, the gardener began to notice a change in the tree, as if it were preparing for something beautiful. But she continued to wander through the meadow, tending to her flowers with new and renewed love. One morning, she awoke in her treehouse and all around her on every branch were dazzling purple and white blossoms. Honey bees and hummingbirds visited and made her acquaintance. She climbed out of her treehouse and up again to the highest branch that would support her. She felt the sway of the branch in the breeze and heard the song of the wind through the leaves, and she lifted up her voice, and together they sang the love, beauty, and truth of the heavens.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Liechty</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/adamliechty</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="writing" term="writing"/>
    </entry>
</feed>